bakernet.com 2018-10-20

# Privacy & Cookies Statement | Baker McKenzie

This Privacy & Cookies Statement describes how Baker McKenzie (the "Firm") collects, uses, shares, and otherwise processes Personal Data (defined below) about:

  * Visitors to our websites, mobile applications, and other online properties (each, a "Site")
  * Contact persons for our clients and/or prospective clients
  * Contact persons for suppliers of goods and services to the Firm
  * Any other individuals about whom the Firm obtains Personal Data

In this Privacy & Cookies Statement, "Personal Data" means information that (either in isolation or in combination with other information held by the Firm) enables you to be identified as an individual or recognized directly or indirectly. 

For the name and contact details of the Baker McKenzie member firm in your jurisdiction, please select your country below:

**Buenos Aires**  
Cecilia Grierson 255, 6th Floor  
Buenos Aires C1107CPE  
Argentina

Tel: +54 11 4310 2200  
Fax: +54 11 4310 2299

**Brisbane**  
Level 8  
175 Eagle Street  
Brisbane QLD 4000  
Australia

Tel: +61 7 3069 6200  
Fax: +61 7 3069 6201

| 

**Melbourne**  
Level 19  
181 William Street  
Melbourne VIC 3000  
Australia

Tel: +61 3 9617 4200  
Fax: +61 3 9614 2103

| 

**Sydney**  
Tower One - International Towers Sydney  
Level 46, 100 Barangaroo Avenue  
Sydney NSW 2000  
Australia

Tel: +61 2 9225 0200  
Fax: +61 2 9225 1595  
  
---|---|---  

**Vienna**  
Schottenring 25  
1010 Vienna  
Austria

Tel: +43 1 24 250  
Fax: +43 1 24 250 600

**Baku**  
The Landmark Building  
90A Nizami Street  
Baku AZ1010  
Azerbaijan

Tel: +994 12 497 18 01  
Fax: +994 12 497 18 05

**Bahrain**  
18th Floor   
West Tower   
Bahrain Financial Harbour   
P.O. Box 11981  
Manama  
Kingdom of Bahrain 

**Antrwerp**  
Meir 24  
2000 Antwerp, Belgium

VAT BE 0426.100.511 RPR Brussels

Tel: +32 3 213 40 40  
Fax: +32 3 213 40 45

| 

**Brussels**  
Louizalaan 149 Avenue Louise, 11th Floor  
1050 Brussels, Belgium

VAT BE 0426.100.511 RPR Brussels

Tel: +32 2 639 36 11  
Fax: +32 2 639 36 99  
  
---|---  
  
**Toronto**  
181 Bay Street, Suite 2100  
Toronto, Ontario M5J 2T3  
Canada

Tel: +1 416 863 1221  
Fax: +1 416 863 6275

**Santiago**  
Avenida Andrés Bello 2457, Piso 19  
Providencia, CL 7510689  
Santiago  
Chile

Tel: +56 2 2367 7000

**Beijing**  
Suite 3401, China World Office 2,  
China World Trade Centre,  
1 Jianguomenwai Dajie,  
Beijing 100004

Tel: +86 10 6535 3800  
Fax: +86 10 6505 2309

| 

**Hong Kong**  
14th Floor, Hutchison House,  
10 Harcourt Road, Central,  
Hong Kong SAR  

Tel: +852 2846 1888  
Fax: +852 2845 0476

| 

**Shanghai**  
Unit 1601, Jin Mao Tower,  
88 Century Avenue, Pudong,  
Shanghai 200121  

Tel: +86 21 6105 8558  
Fax: +86 21 5047 0020  
  
---|---|---  
  
**Bogota**  
Avenue 82 No. 10-62 6th Floor  
Bogota  
Colombia

Tel: +57 1 634 1500 / 644 9595  
Fax: +57 1 376 2211

**Prague**  
Praha City Center  
Klimentská 46  
Prague 110 02  
Czech Republic

Tel: +420 236 045 001  
Fax: +420 236 045 055

**Cairo**  
Nile City Building, North Tower  
21st Floor 2005C, Cornich El Nil  
Ramlet Beaulac  
Cairo  
Egypt

Tel: +20 2 2461 5520  
Fax: +20 2 2461 9302

**Paris**  
1 rue Paul Baudry  
75008 Paris  
France

Tel: + 33 1 4417 5300  
Fax: + 33 1 4417 4575

**Berlin**  
Friedrichstraße 88/Unter den Linden  
10117 Berlin  
Germany

Tel: +49 30 2 20 02 81 0  
Fax: +49 30 2 20 02 81 199

| 

**Dusseldorf**  
Neuer Zollhof 2  
40221 Dusseldorf  
Germany

Tel: +49 211 3 11 16 0  
Fax: +49 211 3 11 16 199  
  
---|---  
  
**Frankfurt**  
Bethmannstrasse 50-54  
60311 Frankfurt/Main  
Germany

Tel: +49 69 2 99 08 0  
Fax: +49 69 2 99 08 108

| 

**Munich**  
Theatinerstrasse 23  
80333 Munich  
Germany

Tel: +49 89 5 52 38 0  
Fax: +49 89 5 52 38 199  
  
**Budapest**  
Dorottya utca 6.  
1051 Budapest  
Hungary

Tel: +36 1 302 3330  
Fax: +36 1 302 3331

**Jakarta**  
HHP Law Firm  
Pacific Century Place, Level 35  
Sudirman Central Business District Lot 10  
Jl. Jendral Sudirman Kav 52-53  
Jakarta 12190  
Indonesia

Tel: +62 21 2960 8888  
Fax: +62 21 2960 8999

**Milan**  
Piazza Meda, 3  
Milan 20121

Tel: +39 02 76231 1  
Fax: +39 02 7623 1620

| 

**Rome**  
Viale di Villa Massimo, 57  
Rome 00161

Tel: +39 06 44 06 31  
Fax: +39 06 4406 3306  
  
---|---  
  
**Tokyo**  
Ark Hills Sengokuyama Mori Tower, 28th Floor  
1-9-10, Roppongi, Minato-ku  
Tokyo 106-0032  
Japan

Tel: +81 3 6271 9900  
Fax: +81 3 5549 7720

**Almaty**  
Samal Towers, 8th Floor  
97, Zholdasbekov Street  
Almaty Samal-2, 050051  
Kazakhstan

Tel: +7 727 330 05 00  
Fax: +7 727 258 40 00

**Luxembourg**  
10 - 12 Boulevard Roosevelt  
Luxembourg 2450  
Luxembourg

Tel: +352 26 18 44 1  
Fax: +352 26 18 44 99

**Kuala Lumpur**  
Wong & Partners, Level 21, The Gardens South Tower  
Mid Valley City  
Lingkaran Syed Putra  
Kuala Lumpur 59200  
Malaysia

Tel: + 603 2298 7888  
Fax: + 603 2282 2669

**Guadalajara**  
Av. Paseo Royal Country 4596  
Torre Cube 2, 16th Floor  
Fracc. Puerta de Hierro  
Zapopan, Jalisco 45116, Mexico

Tel: +52 33 3848 5300  
Fax: +52 33 3848 5399

| 

**Juárez**  
P.O. Box 9338 El Paso, TX 79995  
P.T. de la República 3304, 1st floor  
Juárez, Chihuahua 32330  
Mexico

Tel: +52 656 629 1300  
Fax: +52 656 629 1399

| 

**Mexico City**  
Edificio Virreyes   
Pedregal 24, 12th floor  
Lomas Virreyes / Col. Molino del Rey  
México City, 11040,Mexico

Tel: +52 55 5279 2900  
Fax: +52 55 5279 2999  
  
---|---|---  
  
**Monterrey**  
Oficinas en el Parque  
Torre Baker McKenzie, 10th floor  
Blvd. Antonio L. Rodríguez 1884 Pte.  
Monterrey, N.L. 64650, Mexico

Tel: +52 81 8399 1300  
Fax: +52 81 8399 1399

| 

**Tijuana**  
P.O. Box 1205 Chula Vista, CA 91912  
Blvd. Agua Caliente 10611, 1st floor  
Tijuana, B.C. 22420  
Mexico

Tel: +52 664 633 4300  
Fax: +52 664 633 4399

|   
  
**Casablanca**  
Ghandi Mall - Immeuble 9  
Boulevard Ghandi  
20380 Casablanca  
Morocco

Tel: +212 522 77 95 95  
Fax: +212 522 77 95 96

**Yangon**  
Level 18, Unit 18-03  
Sule Square  
221 Sule Pagoda Road,  
Kyauktada Township  
Yangon  
Myanmar

Tel: +95 1 925 5095

**Amsterdam**  
Claude Debussylaan 54  
1082 MD Amsterdam   
P.O. Box 2720  
1000 CS  
Amsterdam  
The Netherlands

Tel: +31 20 551 7555  
Fax: +31 20 626 7949

**Lima**  
Av. De la Floresta 497  
Piso 5 San Borja  
Lima 41  
Peru

Tel: +51 1 618 8500  
Fax: +51 1 372 7171/ 372 7374

**Manila**  
Quisumbing Torres  
12th Floor, Net One Center  
26th Street Corner 3rd Avenue  
Crescent Park West  
Bonifacio Global City  
Taguig City 1634  
Philippines

Tel: +63 2 819 4700  
Fax: +63 2 816 0080

**Warsaw**  
Rondo ONZ 1  
Warsaw 00-124  
Poland

Tel: +48 22 445 3100  
Fax: +48 22 445 3200

**Doha**  
Al Fardan Office Tower, 8th Floor   
Al Funduq Street  
West Bay  
P.O. Box 31316  
Doha, Qatar

Tel: +974 4410 1817  
Fax: +974 4410 1500

**Moscow**  
White Gardens  
9 Lesnaya Street  
Moscow 125047  
Russia

Tel: +7 495 787 2700  
Fax: +7 495 787 2701

| 

**St. Petersburg**  
BolloevCenter, 2nd Floor  
4A Grivtsova Lane  
St. Petersburg 190000  
Russia

Tel: +7 812 303 9000  
Fax: +7 812 325 6013  
  
---|---  
  
**Jeddah**  
Abdulaziz I. Al-Ajlan & Partners,  
Bin Sulaiman Center, 6th Floor, Office No. 606,  
Al-Khalidiyah District, P.O. Box 128224  
Prince Sultan Street and Rawdah Street Intersection  
Jeddah 21362  
Saudi Arabia

Tel: + 966 12 606 6200  
Fax: + 966 12 692 8001

| 

**Riyadh**  
Abdulaziz I. Al-Ajlan & Partners,  
Olayan Complex  
Tower II, 3rd Floor   
Al Ahsa Street, Malaz   
P.O. Box 69103  
Riyadh 11547,Saudi Arabia

Tel: +966 11 265 8900  
Fax: +966 11 265 8999  
  
---|---  
  
**Singapore**  
8 Marina Boulevard   
#05-01 Marina Bay Financial Centre Tower 1  
Singapore 018981  
Singapore

Tel: +65 6338 1888  
Fax: +65 6337 5100

**Johannesburg**  
1 Commerce Square  
39 Rivonia Road  
Sandhurst  
Sandton  
Johannesburg  
South Africa

Tel: +27 11 911 4300  
Fax: +27 11 784 2855

**Seoul**  
17/F, Two IFC  
10 Gukjegeumyung-ro  
Yeongdeungpo-gu  
Seoul 150-945  
Korea

Tel: +82 2 6137 6800  
Fax: +82 2 6137 9433

**Barcelona**  
Avda. Diagonal, 652  
Edif. D, 8th Floor  
Barcelona 08034  
Spain

Tel: +34 93 206 0820  
Fax: +34 93 205 4959

| 

**Madrid**  
Edificio Beatriz  
C/ José Ortega y Gasset, 29  
Madrid 28006  
Spain

Tel: +34 91 230 4500  
Fax: +34 91 391 5149  
  
---|---  
  
**Stockholm**  
Vasagatan 7, Floor 8  
P.O. Box 180  
Stockholm SE-101 23  
Sweden

Tel: +46 8 566 177 00  
Fax: +46 8 566 177 99

**Geneva**  
Rue Pedro-Meylan 5  
Geneva 1208  
Switzerland

Tel: +41 22 707 9800  
Fax: +41 22 707 9801

| 

**Zurich**  
Holbeinstrasse 30  
Zurich 8034  
Switzerland

Tel: +41 44 384 14 14  
Fax: +41 44 384 12 84  
  
---|---  
  
**Taipei**  
15F, 168 Dunhua North Road  
Taipei 10548  
Taiwan

Tel: +886 2 2712 6151  
Fax: +886 2 2712 8292

**Bangkok**  
25th Floor, Abdulrahim Place  
990 Rama IV Road  
Bangkok 10500  
Thailand

Tel: +66 2636 2000  
Fax: +66 2636 2111

**Istanbul**  
Ebulula Mardin Cad., Gül Sok. No. 2  
Maya Park Tower 2, Akatlar-Beşiktaş  
Istanbul 34335  
Turkey

Tel: + 90 212 339 8100  
Fax: + 90 212 339 8181

**Kyiv**  
Renaissance Business Center  
24 Bulvarno-Kudriavska (Vorovskoho) Street  
Kyiv 01601  
Ukraine

Tel: +380 44 590 0101  
Fax: +380 44 590 0110

**Abu Dhabi**  
Level 8, Al Sila Tower  
Abu Dhabi Global Market Square  
Al Maryah Island, P.O. Box 44980  
Abu Dhabi  
United Arab Emirates

Tel: +971 2 696 1200  
Fax: +971 2 676 6477

| 

**Dubai**  
Level 14, O14 Tower  
Al Abraj Street  
Business Bay, P.O. Box 2268  
Dubai  
United Arab Emirates

Tel: +971 4 423 0000  
Fax: +971 4 447 9777

| 

**Dubai - DIFC**  
Level 3, Tower 1  
Al Fattan Currency House  
DIFC, P.O. Box 2268  
Dubai  
United Arab Emirates

Tel: +971 4 423 0005  
Fax: +971 4 447 9777  
  
---|---|---  
  
**London**  
100 New Bridge Street  
London EC4V 6JA  
UK

Tel: +44 20 7919 1000  
Fax: +44 20 7919 1999

| 

**Belfast**  
City Quays One   
7 Clarendon Road   
Belfast BT1 3BG  
UK

Tel: +44 28 9555 5000  
  
---|---  
  
**Chicago**  
300 East Randolph Street, Suite 5000  
Chicago, Illinois 60601  
United States

Tel: +1 312 861 8000  
Fax: +1 312 861 2899

| 

**Dallas**  
1900 North Pearl Street, Suite 1500  
Dallas, Texas 75201  
United States

Tel: +1 214 978 3000  
Fax: +1 214 978 3099

| 

**Houston**  
700 Louisiana, Suite 3000  
Houston, Texas 77002  
United States

Tel: +1 713 427 5000  
Fax: +1 713 427 5099  
  
---|---|---  
  
**Los Angeles**  
1901 Avenue of the Stars, Suite 950  
Los Angeles, California 90067  
United States

Tel: +1 310 201 4728  
Fax: +1 310 201 4721

| 

**Miami**  
1111 Brickell Avenue, Suite 1700  
Miami, Florida 33131  
United States

Tel: +1 305 789 8900  
Fax: +1 305 789 8953

| 

**New York**  
452 Fifth Avenue  
New York, New York 10018  
United States

Tel: +1 212 626 4100  
Fax: +1 212 310 1600  
  
**Palo Alto**  
660 Hansen Way  
Palo Alto, California 94304  
United States

Tel: +1 650 856 2400  
Fax: +1 650 856 9299

| 

**San Francisco**  
Two Embarcadero Center, Suite 1100  
San Francisco, California 94111  
United States

Tel: +1 415 576 3000  
Fax: +1 415 576 3099

| 

**Washington, DC**  
815 Connecticut Avenue, N.W.  
Washington, District of Columbia 20006  
United States

Tel: +1 202 452 7000  
Fax: +1 202 452 7074  
  
**Caracas**  
Centro Bancaribe, Intersección   
Avenida Principal de Las Mercedes   
con inicio de Calle París,  
Urbanización Las Mercedes  
Caracas 1060, Venezuela

Tel: +58 212 276 5111  
Fax: +58 212 993 0818; 993 9049

| 

**Valencia**  
World Trade Center  
8th floor, Office 8-A  
Av. 168 Salvador Feo la Cruz Este-Oeste   
Naguanagua 2005, Valencia Estado Carabobo  
Venezuela

Tel: + 58 241 824 8711  

---|---  
  
**Hanoi**  
Unit 1001, 10th floor,  Indochina Plaza Hanoi   
241 Xuan Thuy Street, Cau Giay District  
Hanoi 10000  
Vietnam

Tel: +84 24 3825 1428  
Fax: +84 24 3825 1432

| 

**Ho Chi Minh City**  
12th Floor, Saigon Tower  
29 Le Duan Blvd  
District 1  
Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Tel: +84 28 3829 5585  
Fax: +84 28 3829 5618  
  
---|---  
  
LawInContext Pte. Ltd. (Singapore) Zurich Branch  
Holbeinstrasse 30  
8008 Zurich  
Switzerland 

### Overview

Unless we specifically state otherwise, the Firm is the data controller of the Personal Data we process, and is therefore responsible for ensuring that the systems and processes we use are compliant with data protection laws, to the extent applicable to us.

Firm personnel are required to comply with this Privacy & Cookies Statement and associated Firm policies when dealing with Personal Data and must also complete data protection training where appropriate to their role.

### Summary of Key Points

**Collection** | We collect Personal Data from a number of sources in connection with the day-to-day management of our business and our commercial relationships.  Click here to learn more.  
---|---  
**Use** | We use Personal Data to provide our services and respond to inquiries, to manage accounts and maintain business operations, to provide relevant marketing, and to fulfill other business and compliance purposes. Click here to learn more.   
  
**Sharing** | We share Personal Data as necessary to provide our services and respond to requests, and to fulfil other business and compliance purposes. Click here to learn more.   
**Marketing Choices** | You have control on how we use Personal Data for marketing. Click here to learn more.  
**Cookies** | We use cookies on our Sites, and provide choices on use of cookies, including third party targeting and advertising. Click here to learn more.  
**Data Subject Rights** | You have certain rights to request access, rectification, deletion, objection, or other actions regarding your Personal Data where required by applicable law. Click here to learn more.  
**Data Security** | We maintain technical and organizational measures to protect Personal Data from loss, misuse, alteration, or unintentional destruction of Personal Data. Click here to learn more.  
**Cross-Border Data Transfers** | We provide appropriate protections for cross-border transfers where specified by law. Click here to learn more.   
**Other Issues** | We provide other information in this Privacy & Cookies Statement about: (i) the possible consequences for not providing Personal Data, (ii) how we do not engage in automated decision-making that has substantial effects on individuals, (iii) how we handle do-not-track (DNT) signals, (iv) data retention, (v) links to third party websites, (vi) employee and contractor issues; and (vii) changes to this Privacy & Cookies Statement. Click here to learn more.   
**Contact Us** | Please contact us as detailed below with any questions. Click here to learn more.  
  
### Collection of Personal Data

We collect the following categories of Personal Data about Site visitors, clients, prospective clients, suppliers and other third parties:

  * **Basic data:** Name, gender, title, organization, job responsibilities, phone number, mailing address, email address, contact details and information about family life (excluding special categories of data) including family, children, hobbies and interests .
  * **Special categories of data:** in limited circumstances, where you have provided us with such information as it is necessary for a specific service we are providing to you: religious or other beliefs, racial or ethnic origin,  sexual orientation, health data and details of trade union membership.
  * **Registration data:  ** Newsletter requests, event/seminar registrations, dietary preferences (excluding special categories of data), subscriptions, downloads, and username/passwords.
  * **Client service data:  ** Personal Data received from clients in respect of employees, customers or other individuals known to clients,  invoicing details and payment history, and client feedback.   
  * **Marketing data:** Data about individual participation in conferences and in-person seminars, credentials, associations, product interests, and preferences. 
  * **Compliance data:** Government identifiers, passports or other identification documents, dates of birth, beneficial ownership data, and due diligence data.
  * **Job applicant data:  ** Data provided by job applicants or others on our Sites or offline means in connection with employment opportunities, which also may be subject to an additional relevant local recruitment privacy policy.  
  * **Device data:** Computer Internet Protocol (IP) address, unique device identifier (UDID), cookies and other data linked to a device, and data about usage of our Sites (Usage Data). 

We collect Personal Data from a number of sources, either directly from the data subjects,  or from clients, colleagues and publically available sources. Where the Firm receives data from its clients about employees, customers or other individuals, the client  is responsible for ensuring that any such data is transferred to us in compliance with applicable data protection laws. 

### Use of Personal Data

The purposes for which we use Personal Data, and the legal bases for such processing, are as follows: 

  * To **provide legal advice and respond to inquiries** we use basic data, registration data, client service data, and device data.  We need to process your information in this way in order to perform our obligations under our contracts with our clients. 
  * To **manage our business operations and administer our client relationships** we use basic data, special categories of data, registration data, marketing data and client service data.  This processing is necessary in order to perform our obligations under our contracts with our clients (e.g. issuing and processing invoices) and suppliers (e.g. managing the supply of goods and services to the Firm). 
  * To **make our Sites more intuitive and easy to use** we use device data.  It is necessary for our legitimate interests to monitor how our Sites are used to help us improve the layout and information available on our Sites and provide a better service to our Site users.
  * To **protect the security and effective functioning of our Sites and information technology systems** we use basic data, registration data, transaction data, and device data.  It is necessary for our legitimate interests to monitor how our Sites are used to detect and prevent fraud, other crimes and the misuse of our Sites. This helps us to ensure that you can safely use our Sites.
  * To **provide relevant marketing   **such as providing you with information about events or services that may be of interest to you including legal services, legal updates, client conferences or networking events, and groups of specific interest (e.g. specific types of networking groups) we use marketing data, basic data, special categories of data, registration data, client service data, and device data. It is necessary for our legitimate interests to process this information in order to provide you with tailored and relevant marketing, updates and invitations.
  * To **address compliance and legal obligations** , such as checking the identity of new clients and to prevent money laundering and/or fraud we use compliance data, basic data, registration data, transaction data, and device data. This processing is necessary for the purposes of complying with legal requirements to which we are subject.
  * To **consider individuals for employment and contractor opportunities and manage on-boarding procedures** we use job applicant data and compliance data. The processing is necessary for the purposes of recruitment and on-boarding and for complying with legal obligations to which we are subject and which may be subject to a relevant local recruitment privacy policy.

### Sharing of Personal Data

We may share Personal Data with the following categories of recipients:

  * **Affiliates:  **Baker McKenzie operates under the umbrella of Baker McKenzie International, a Swiss Verein, with member law firms around the world. Each member firm may share Personal Data with other member law firms in order to provide you with legal services and in order to administer our relationship with you (e.g. invoicing, marketing)  or otherwise as necessary for the purposes described above. We may also share Personal Data with our global services companies in Belfast, Chicago and Manila. A list of Baker McKenzie member firms is provided here.
  * **Suppliers and service providers:** We share Personal Data with suppliers and service providers to enable such parties to perform functions on our behalf and under our instructions in order to carry out the purposes identified above.  These include: infrastructure and IT services providers, for example, the providers of our client intake system, our finance systems and our customer relationship management databases; third party consultants who provide us with support in respect of business analytics and marketing campaigns; and the providers of external venues where we host conferences and events. We require such parties by contract to provide reasonable security for Personal Data and to use and process such Personal Data on our behalf only.
  * **Financial institutions:** We share Personal Data with financial institutions in connection with invoicing and payments.
  * **Corporate purchasers:** We may share Personal Data with any corporate purchaser or prospect to the extent permitted by law as part of any merger, acquisition, sale of Firm assets, or transition of service to another provider, as well as in the event of insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which Personal Data would be transferred as an asset of the Firm.
  * **Mandatory disclosures and legal claims:** We share Personal Data in order to comply with any subpoena, court order or other legal process, to comply with a request from our regulators, governmental request or any other legally enforceable demand.  We also share Personal Data to establish or protect our legal rights, property, or safety, or the rights, property, or safety of others, or to defend against legal claims.

If you have questions about the parties with which we share Personal Data, please contact us as specified below. 

### Marketing Choices

**You have control regarding our use of Personal Data for direct marketing**. In certain markets, you will need to expressly consent before receiving marketing.  In all markets, **you can choose to not receive such communications at any time**. If you no longer wish to receive any marketing communications, remain on a mailing list to which you previously subscribed, or receive any other marketing communication,  please follow the unsubscribe link in the relevant communication or contact us as per below.

### Cookies

We use and allow certain third parties to use cookies, web beacons, and similar tracking technologies (collectively, " **cookies** ") on our Sites. 

**What are cookies?**  
Cookies are small amounts of data that are stored on your browser, device, or the page you are viewing. Some cookies are deleted once you close your browser, while other cookies are retained even after you close your browser so that you can be recognized when you return to a websites. More information about cookies and how they work is available at [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**How do we use cookies?**  
We use cookies to provide the Sites and services, gather information about your usage patterns when you navigate this Sites in order to enhance your personalized experience, and to understand usage patterns to improve our Sites, products, and services.  We also allow certain third parties to place cookies on our Sites in order to collect information about your online activities on our Sites over time and across different websites you visit. This information is used to provide advertising tailored to your interests on websites you visit, also known as interest based advertising, and to analyze the effectiveness of such advertising.

Cookies on our Sites are generally divided into the following categories:

  * **Strictly Necessary Cookies:** These are required for the operation of our Sites. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas. These cookies are session cookies that are erased when you close your browser.
  * **Analytical/Performance Cookies:** These allow us to recognize and count the number of users of our Sites and understand how such users navigate through our Sites. This helps to improve how our Sites works, for example, by ensuring that users can find what they are looking for easily. These cookies are session cookies which are erased when you close your browser.  We use Google Analytics, and you can see below for how to control the use of cookies by Google Analytics.
  * **Functional Cookies:** These improve the functional performance of our Sites and make it easier for you to use. For example, cookies are used to remember that you have previously visited the Sites and asked to remain logged into it. These cookies qualify as persistent cookies, because they remain on your device for us to use during a next visit to our Sites.  You can delete these cookies via your browser settings.
  * **Targeting Cookies:** These record your visit to our Sites, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed to recognize you as a previous visitor and to track your activity on the Sites and other websites you visit. These cookies qualify as persistent cookies, because they remain on your device for us to use during a next visit to our Sites. You can delete these cookies via your browser settings. See below for further details on how you can control third party targeting cookies.

**What are your options if you do not want cookies on your computer?**  
You can review your Internet browser settings, typically under the sections "Help" or "Internet Options," to exercise choices you have for certain Cookies. If you disable or delete certain Cookies in your Internet browser settings, you might not be able to access or use important functions or features of this Sites, and you may be required to re-enter your log-in details. 

To learn more about the use of cookies for Google analytics and to exercise choice regarding such cookies, please visit the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

To learn more about certain cookies used for interest based advertising by third parties, including through cross-device tracking, and to exercise certain choices regarding such cookies, please visit the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/), [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#/), [Digital Advertising Alliance-Canada](http://youradchoices.ca/choices), [European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance ](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)or your device settings if you have the DAA or other mobile app.

### Data Subject Rights

If you are in the European Economic Area (EEA) you have the following rights: 

  * **Access.** Subject to certain exceptions , you have the right to request a copy of the Personal Data we are processing about you, which we will provide to you in electronic form. At our discretion we may require you to prove your identity before providing the requested information.  If you require multiple copies of your Personal Data, we may charge a reasonable administration fee. 
  * **Rectification.** You have the right to require that any incomplete or inaccurate Personal Data that we process about you is amended. 
  * **Deletion.** You have the right to request that we delete Personal Data that we process about you, unless we are required to retain such data in order to comply with a legal obligation or to establish, exercise or defend legal claims. 
  * **Restriction.** You have the right to request that we restrict our processing of your Personal Data where: 
    * you believe such data to be inaccurate; 
    * our processing is unlawful; or 
    * we no longer need to process such data for a particular purpose, but where we are not able to delete the data due to a legal or other obligation or because you do not want us to delete it. 
  * **Portability.** You have the right to request that we transmit the Personal Data we hold in respect of you to another data controller, where this is: 
    * personal information which you have provided to us; and 
    * we are processing that data on the basis of your consent or in order to perform our obligations under contract to you (such as to provide legal services). 
  * **Objection.** Where the legal justification for our processing of your Personal Data is our legitimate interest, you have the right to object to such processing on grounds relating to your particular situation.  We will abide by your request unless we have compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests and rights, or if we need to continue to process the data for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim.
  * **Withdrawing Consent.  ** If you have consented to our processing of your Personal Data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, free of charge  This includes cases where you wish to opt out from marketing messages that you receive from us. 

If you are in the EEA you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the local data protection authority if you believe that we have not complied with applicable data protection laws.[ Access a list of local data protection authorities in EEA countries.](http://ec.europa.eu/newsroom/article29/item-detail.cfm?item_id=612080)

### Data Security

We have implemented technical and organisational measures in an effort to safeguard the Personal Data in our custody and control. Such measures include:

  * restricting access to Personal Data to staff and service providers on a need-to-know basis;
  * a formal Information Security Management System (ISMS) aligned with ISO 27001 and 27002:2013.  The ISMS is a comprehensive set of policies and procedures for deploying, managing and securing the Firm's Information Technology infrastructure; utilizing a defense-in-depth approach to protecting our internal Firm and client data. 

While we endeavour to always protect our systems, sites, operations and information against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure, due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle and other risk factors, we cannot guarantee that any information, during transmission or while stored on our systems, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others.

You also have an important role in protecting Personal Data. You should not share any username, password or other authentication data provided to you with anyone, and we recommend that you do not re-use passwords across more than one website or application.  If you have any reason to believe that your username or password has been compromised, please contact us as detailed below.

### Cross-Border Data Transfers

We transfer Personal Data to jurisdictions as necessary for the purposes described above, including to jurisdictions that may not provide the same level of data protection as your home country.  In particular, our Sites are hosted on servers in the United States.  If you are located in a non-US jurisdiction, the transfer of Personal Data is necessary to provide you with the requested information and/or to perform any requested transaction.  To the extent permitted by law, such submission also constitutes your consent for the cross-border transfer. 

With respect to transfers originating from the European Economic Area ("EEA") to the United States and other non-EEA jurisdictions, we implement standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission, and other appropriate solutions to address cross-border transfers as required or permitted by Articles 46 and 49 of the General Data Protection Regulation.  Where required by such laws, you may request a copy of the suitable mechanisms we have in place by contacting us as detailed below. 

### Other Issues

  1. **What are the consequences of not providing Personal Data?**  
You are not required to provide all Personal Data identified in this Privacy & Cookies Statement to use our Sites or to interact with us offline, but certain functionality will not be available if you do not provide Personal Data.  If you do not provide Personal Data, we may not be able to respond to your request, provide legal services to  you, or provide you with marketing that we believe you would find valuable.     
  2. **Do we engage in automated decision-making without human intervention?**  
We do not use automated decision-making without human intervention, including profiling, in a way that produces legal effects concerning you or otherwise significantly affects you.
  3. **Do the Sites honor do not track ("DNT") signals sent via browsers?**  
Given the divergent practices of organizations that offer browsers and the lack of a standard in the marketplace, we generally do not respond to DNT signals at this time.
  4. **How long do we retain Personal Data?**  
We typically retain Personal Data related to marketing activities for as long as you accept marketing communications from us, and we will securely delete such data in accordance with applicable law upon request.  For Personal Data that we collect and process for other purposes, we will typically retain such Personal Data for as long as it is necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy & Cookies Statement and as otherwise specified in applicable record retention policies and procedures. 
  5. **Are third party websites governed by this Privacy & Cookies Statement? **  
The Sites may contain links and references to other websites administered by unaffiliated third parties.  This Privacy & Cookies Statement does not apply to such third party sites.  When you click a link to visit a third party website, you will be subject to that website's privacy practices.  We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy and security practices of any linked third party websites before providing any Personal Data on that website.
  6. **How does the Firm handle employee and contractor privacy issues?**  
Personal Data about our employees and contractors are addressed through internal Firm policies and procedures, and are outside the scope of this Privacy & Cookies Statement.
  7. **How will we handle any changes to this Privacy & Cookies Statement? **  
We may update this Privacy & Cookies Statement from time to time as our services and privacy practices change, or as required by law.  The effective date of our Privacy & Cookies Statement is posted below, and we encourage you to visit our Sites periodically to stay informed about our privacy practices.  We will post the updated version of the Privacy & Cookies Statement on our Sites, and ask for your consent to the changes if legally required.

### Contact Us

If you have questions or comments regarding this Privacy & Cookies Statement or our privacy practices, please contact us here: 

City Quays One   
7 Clarendon Road   
Belfast   
N. Ireland   
BT13BG 

The Firm's Global Services Group in Belfast, Northern Ireland, is the local representative in the European Union for the entity that operates this Site, Baker McKenzie LLP, 300 E. Randolph Street, Chicago, Illinois, USA. Niall McSorley is in the Firm's Global Services Group and, with Peter Engstrom the Firm's General Counsel, is responsible for the content of this Privacy & Cookies Statement.

**Effective date: 25 May 2018  
**
